Guide to the City and Regional Planning Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
City and regional planning collection
1873-2000
MS 1970
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
21.25
(44 boxes)
The collection consists of reports by city, local, and regional planning agencies spanning approximately from 1873 to 2000. The geographic range of the reports is global, but is focused mainly on Southeastern Connecticut and New Haven, though many smaller towns and cities in Connecticut are also represented. More general reports about the New York region and other states, socioeconomic data about the United States, and scattered documentation about urban planning in other countries are also part of this collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series: Series I. City Planning Connecticut, 1912-1980. Series II. State and International Planning, 1914-1990. Series III. City Planning Subject Files, 1873-2000, and alphabetically therein.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of reports by city, local, and regional planning agencies spanning approximately from 1873 to 2000. The geographic range of the reports is global, but is focused mainly on Southeastern Connecticut and New Haven, though many smaller towns and cities in Connecticut are also represented. More general reports about the New York region and other states, socioeconomic data about the United States, and scattered documentation about urban planning in other countries are also part of this collection.
Development plans, transportation studies, water resources inventories, park and recreation plans, urban renewal reports, housing market indexes, labor and employment statistics, demographic information, industry and manufacturing data, and planning and zoning reports are included. Of note are a series of reports, "Community Monographs," produced by the Research Division of the Connecticut Development Commission in Hartford. In some instances, these detailed community profiles were collected over a span of many years, which provides insight to the changes in a city or town's development over time.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Haas Family Arts Library, 2010.
Cities and towns -- Growth; City planning -- Connecticut; City planning; Housing; Land use; Regional planning; Urban renewal; Connecticut
- City Planning Connecticut, 1912-1986; Series I
  - Ansonia, Community Monographs, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Avon, Community Monographs, 1957, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Town of Berlin Connecticut, Subdivision Regulations, 1949 September (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bethel, Community Monographs, 1956, 1960, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  - Bloomfield, Community Monographs, 1957, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Bolton, Community Monographs, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Town of Bozrah, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Branford, Annual Reports, 1977 July-1980 June (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
  - Bridgeport
    - City of Bridgeport, State Street Urban Renewal Area, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Community Monographs, 1962, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - The First Ten Years: Brand-New Bridgeport, 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Potentialities of The Central Business District, 1961 October (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bridgeport, Greater Region
    - Annual Report, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Financing The Regional Plan of Development, 1967 August (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Future Sewage System, 1965 June (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Harbor and Waterfront Land Use Inventory Planning Potentials, 1969 January (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Health Facilities In The Greater Bridgeport Region, 1967 June (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Housing In The Greater Bridgeport Region, 1960-1980, 1965 July (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Housing In The Greater Bridgeport Region, 1969-1970, 1970 May (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Libraries Present Resources And Future Needs, 1964-2000, 1966 July (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Open Space, Needs And Resources, 1964 September (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Open Space, Needs And Resources, 1960-2000, 1965 June (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Open Space Plan and Program, 1969 March (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Planning for the Region, 1976 January (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Population Projections, 1964-1967 April (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
    - Preliminary Regional Plan, 1963 June (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Preliminary Regional Plan For Sewerage And Drainage, 1965 February (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Profile Of Six Neighborhoods in The City Of Bridgeport, 1965 July (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Projected School Needs And Resources, 1960-2000, 1965 January (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Towards A Regional Plan Of Development: Status of Economic Growth, 1977 March (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Regional Plan Of Development: A Summary Report, 1968 May (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Regional Reporter, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Transportation Study, Final Report, 1967 June (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Water Resources In The Greater Bridgeport Region,1968-1980-2000-2020, 1969 April (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bristol
    - Community Monographs, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bristol Market Report, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Brookfield, Community Monographs, 1956, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Brooklyn, Community Monographs, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Central Connecticut Region
    - Regional Resources, A Report On The Human, Economic And Environmental Resources Of The Central Connecticut Planning Region, 1968 April (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Regional Development Action Plan: A Policies Plan for the Central Connecticut Planning Region, 1969 March (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cheshire, Community Monographs, 1959, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
  - Chester, Community Monographs, 1959, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - Colchester, Community Monographs, 1956, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - Coventry, Community Monographs, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cromwell, A Comprehensive Plan, 1967 January (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Danbury
    - Analysis Of The Danbury, Connecticut Housing Market as of December 1, 1967, 1968 June (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Community Monographs, 1956, 1962, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 17-19)
  - Danbury-New Milford, Market Report, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - Durham, Community Monographs, 1958, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
  - East Granby
    - Environmental Impact Statement, 1975 November (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Plan Of Development Questionnaire, 1974 July (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - East Hartford
    - Community Monographs, 1957, 1960, 1967, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 26-29)
    - Town Of East Hartford, Connecticut General Development Plan, 1962 November (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - East Haven
    - Community Monographs, 1959, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Comprehensive Plan For The Town of East Haven, 1966 October (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Neighborhood Analyses And Urban Renewal Program For The Town Of East Haven, Connecticut, 1966 September (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Zoning Map, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - East Lyme, Uniform Fiscal Year Conversion Study, 1974 September (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ellington, Community Monographs, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Enfield
    - Brainerd Park Plan, 1973 September (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Community Monographs, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Town of Enfield School Bus Study, 1975 December (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Enfield-Windsor Locks, Market Report, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Fairfield
    - Community Monographs, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Transportation Tomorrow In Fairfield County, Problems And Prospects, 1966 October (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Farmington
    - The Economic Outlook, 1956 December (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Political Organization And The Planning Of Water Resource Development In The Farmington Valley, 1967 October (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Town Of Farmington Flood Plain Regulations, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Glastonbury, Community Monographs, 1957, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
  - Greenwich
    - Land Use, 1963 August (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - The People Of Greenwich, Analysis of The 1960 Census Of Population And Housing, 1962 November (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Griswold, Community Monographs, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Groton, A Report to The Community Center Study Committee, 1976 April (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Guilford
    - Community Monographs, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Comprehensive Plan of Development, 1965 October (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Land SubDivision Regulations, 1956 August (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Market Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
    - Proposals For Recreational Use Of The Former Bittner Property, 1975 August (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Zoning Map, 1966 October (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Hamden
    - Community Monographs, 1960, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Community Survey Of Hamden, Connecticut, 1967 November (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Land Use Plan, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Plan Of Development Summary Report, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Traffic Studies And Expressway And Major Street Plan, 1964 September (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Hartford
    - Annual Report, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Community Monographs, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Community Renewal Program, 1964 October (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Hartford Market Report, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - A Plan For The City Of Hartford, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Kent, Community Monographs, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Killingly, Community Monographs, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
  - Ledyard, Community Monographs, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Madison, Annual Reports, 1977-1978, 1980, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 16-19)
  - Manchester, Community Monographs, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Meriden
    - Central Business District Plan, 1959 December (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Circulation Plan, 1959 August (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - City of Meriden Management Analysis, 1975 November (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Community Facilities Plan, 1960 May (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Community Monographs, 1956, 1962, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
    - Community Renewal Program, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Fleet Management Observations And Recommendations, 1975 August (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Land Use Analysis, Neighborhood Analysis, Urban Renewal Plan, 1960 May (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Land Use Plan, 1960 July (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Market Report, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - A Plan For Centralized Purchasing, 1975 July (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Regulatory Controls And Capital Improvement Program, 1960 September (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Middletown
    - Community Monographs, 1957, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
    - Community Renewal Program, 1964 September (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Market Reports, 1969-1971, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 18-21)
  - Milford, Community Monographs, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Monroe, Community Monographs, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Town of Montville, Capital Improvements Program, 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Naugatuck
    - Community Monographs, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Preliminary Survey And Planning Report For The South Main Street Area, Undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Naugatuck Valley Region, Central
    - Helicopters In The Central Naugatuck Valley Region, 1968 January (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Open Space Standards And Criteria, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Plans Of Development, 1962 March (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Population Projection, 1961 June (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - The Proposed General Plan of Regional Development, 1963 November (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Proposed General Plan of Regional Development Maps, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Refuse Disposal Methods in the Central Naugatuck Valley Region, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Report Of The: Route 69 Industrial Development Study Committee, 1966 March (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Land Use Controls Subdivision Regulations, 1961 December (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - New Britain
    - Community Monographs, 1960, 1963, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
    - Market Report, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - New Fairfield, Proposed Renovation and Expansion Of The New Fairfield Town Park, 1976 February (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - New Haven, Community Monographs, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - New London
    - Community Development Program Profile, 1978 October (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Fishing Industry Feasibility Study, 1979 July (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Market Report, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - New London Area, Community Monographs, 1958, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
  - New Milford, Personnel Rules And Regulations, 1975 September (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Newington, Community Monographs, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - North Canaan, Community Monographs, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - North Haven
    - Charter Of The Town of North Haven, Connecticut, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Community Monographs, 1956, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - North Stonington, Community Monographs, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Norwalk
    - Community Monographs, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Labor Market Area, 1965 October (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Market Reports, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 8-10)
    - Master Plan Report, Subdivisions Land Development in Norwalk, 1949-1957 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Master Plan of Transportation, 1955 November (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Traffic Study, Route U.S.1 Norwalk (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Norwich
    - Community Monographs, 1956, 1958, 1962, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 14-17)
    - Market Report, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Old Saybrook, Community Monographs, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Orange
    - Annual Town Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 20-21)
    - Community Monographs, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Oxford, Comprehensive Plan, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Plainfield, Community Monographs, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Plainville, Community Monographs, 1956, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 25-26)
  - Portland, Intersection And Circulation Study, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Preston, Feasibility Study For Town Purchase Of Property At Amos Lake, 1975 November (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Ridgefield, Memorandum On The Evans Property, 1967 December (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Rockville Area, Community Monographs, 1957, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 30-31)
  - Rocky Hill, Community Monographs, 1961, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Seymour, Community Monographs, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Shelton, Community Monographs, 1956, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
  - Sherman, Master Plan Of Development, 1978 January (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Simsbury, Community Monographs, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - South Central
    - Elderly And Handicapped Transportation, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Interstate-95 East Shore Quinnipiac River Bridge Approaches, 1985 October (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Southeastern Regional
    - Report of Water Supply Management Study, 1971 December (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Annual Reports of the Southeastern Connecticut Regional Planning Agency (SCRPA), 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Southington, Community Monographs, 1956, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
  - South Windsor, Community Monographs, 1957, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 15-16)
  - Stamford
    - Citizen's Action Council Annual Reports, 1963-1964, 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 17-20)
    - Community Renewal Program: Goals For Stamford, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - The Economy Of Stamford, Connecticut, Its Components And Capabilities: Labor Force, 1968 March (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - The Economy Of Stamford, Connecticut, Its Components And Capabilities: Population Analysis, 1967 April (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Urban Blight, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Stonington
    - Community Monographs, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Park Plan for the Stoning Recreation Area, 1974 November (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Stratford
    - Community Monographs, 1956, 1960, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - Proposals For Plan Of Development, 1956 June (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Suffield Recreation Plan, 1976-1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Torrington, Community Monographs, 1957, 1962, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 6-8)
  - Trumbull
    - Community Monographs, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - A Pilot Plan For Trumbull, 1954 November (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Valley Region
    - Recommended Regional Plan For Sewerage, Water Supply And Storm Drainage, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Volume IV-Inventory And Analysis Of Existing Water Supply Systems And Potential Sources Of Supply, 1970 February (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Volume V-Storm Drainage: Inventory And Analysis Of Major Existing And Planned Facilities, 1970 February (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Wallingford
    - Annual Report, 1970 June (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Community Monographs, 1962-1968 (Box 10, Folder 15-16)
    - Wallingford Transit, 1986 July (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Warren
    - Plan Of Development-Warren, 1974 October (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Transportation Study, Undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Waterbury, Community Monographs, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Watertown, Community Monographs, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - West Hartford, Community Monographs, 1956, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 22-23)
  - West Haven
    - Annual Report, Outlook, 1967-1970 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
    - Community Monograph s, 1959, 1966, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 6-8)
    - History Of West Haven, Connecticut, 1648-1940 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Savin Rock Urban Renewal Project #2, Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Westport
    - A Survey Of Westport, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - The Westport Journey To Work, 1958 March (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Wethersfield, City Monographs, 1959, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 13-14)
  - Willimantic, Labor Market Area, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Willington
    - Community Monographs, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Natural Factors Affecting the Use of Land, 1974 July (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Winchester
    - Community Monographs, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Parking Study, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - A Study For A Pilot Plan, Undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Windham
    - Community Monographs, 1957, 1961, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 21-23)
    - Health Care Practices, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Housing Strategy, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Windsor, Community Monographs, 1957, 1965, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 26-28)
  - Windsor Locks
    - Community Monographs, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Proposed Construction Of Recreational Facilities At Southwest School, 1975 May (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Proposed Recreational Facilities At Spring Park, 1976 January (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Senior Center Feasibility Study, 1975 September (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Winsted, Redevelopment Proposals For The Center Of Winsted/Winchester, 1974 September (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Woodbridge, Leisure Time Questionnaire, 1976 October (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Woodstock
    - Community Monographs, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Town Hall Space Needs Study, 1975 August (Box 12, Folder 8)
- State and International Planning, 1914-1990; Series II
  - Connecticut
    - A Planned County Emerges, 1938 October (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Business
      - An Analysis Of Market Potentials, 1978 October (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Dwight Neighborhood Planning Team, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - The How And Whys Of Moving, 1966 October (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - The Human Story: 1967, Annual Report of Community Progress, Incorporated (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Major Industrial Opportunities For New Haven, 1966 June (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - The Middle Ground: A Program For New Haven's Middle-Aged Neighborhoods, 1959 September (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - New Haven Citizens Action Commission Annual Report, 1964, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 8-10)
      - New Haven, New England's Newest City, Undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Community Facilities
      - Cultural Arts Resources and Conditions, 1963 March (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Conservation and Rehabilitation
      - Report On Code Enforcement And The Division Of Neighborhood Improvement, 1969 February (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Department of Health
      - Annual Report of Vital Statistics for the City of New Haven, 1975-1976, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 14-16)
    - Development Trends, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Education and Educational Facilities
      - Community Development In Colleges And Universities of The United States, Undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - Connecticut Public Schools Professional Data, 1986 Jan, 1988 June (Box 13, Folder 19-20)
      - Elementary Classes By Size In Connecticut Public Schools, 1985, 1987, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 21-23)
      - Local Public School Expenses and State Aid in Connecticut, 1986 June (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Fifteenth Anniversary Number, 1939 August (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Growth And Change, Issues For The '90s, 1988 September (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Health and Welfare, 1933
      - "Our Neighbors", 1933 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Housing
      - Connecticut Housing Production And Permit Authorized Construction, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Housing In New Haven, Circa 1954 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Housing Trends and Housing Need in the South Central Region of Connecticut-1988, 1987 December (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Land
      - Connecticut Land Type Maps, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Land for Development
      - Connecticut Open Space Grant-In-Aid Program, 1963 November (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Enabling Legislation: Open Space Land Acquisition Recreation Authority, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Revisions that Apply To The Open Space Grant Program, 1969 July (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Technical Release. Conneticut's Shoreline, 1962 December (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Local Finance
      - Compensation of Municipal Officials in Connecticut, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Connecticut Municipal Budgets, 1984-1988 (Box 14, Folder 10-12)
    - Municipal Government
      - Annual Housing Market Report, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Annual Reports of the City of New Haven, 1961, 1963-1968, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 14-21)
      - Highlights of Annual Report, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - New Haven, A Handbook Of Local Government, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - State Of The City Message, 1969 February (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - New Directions in Connecticut Planning Legislation, 1967 February (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - New Haven Annual State of the City Message, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - New Haven's Summer Programs, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - New Parks and Homes, 1934 June (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Outdoor Recreation Needs, 1965 April (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Preliminary Report To Mayor's Committee On Urban Beautification, 1966 March (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Progress Toward Regional Planning In Connecticut, 1959 March (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Public Finance
      - Analysis Of the Governor's State Budget for 1988 and 1990 With Budget Trends, 1987, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
    - Schools
      - Architectural Program for the Wooster Square School-Community Center, Undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Hillhouse Progress Report, 1968 April (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Stepping-Stones From the Slums, Undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Special Census Of Metropolitan New Haven, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Traffic and Parking
      - City of New Haven Annual Reports, 1963, 1965-1967, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 14-18)
      - Temple Street Garage Parking Guide, Undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Transportation
      - Elderly and Handicapped Transportation, 1985 June (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - Transportation Plan Towards The Year 2000, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Urban Institutions
      - Yale in New Haven, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - Yale University, The Report of the President, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Urban Renewal
      - An Act Concerning The Development of Connecticut's Municipalities, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Review of Progress under the Workable Program For Community Improvement, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - This Is Our City, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Urban Renewal In Connecticut, Annual Report, 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
      - Urban Renewal In Connecticut, Statistical Report, 1964, 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 6-8)
      - USA Tomorrow, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 9)